# **Lewis Douglas McDonald Munro**

Address: 36 Main Street, Gullane, East Lothian, EH31 2AA

Email: Lewism1912@gmail.com Mobile: 07713848758

## **Personal statement**

Highly innovative post-graduate with an upper second bachelor's degree in Computer Science from the University of Glasgow. Focused and dedicated with a desire to enhance my strong technical foundation. Energetic and determined, offering 4 years of experience in software development. Seeking an opportunity to develop and implement my key skills in a professional working environment.

# **Key Skills**

- Software Development
- App and Website development
- Debugging and stress testing

- Python, Java, C, HTML, CSS, Haskel
- Github/ Gitlab deployment
- Machine Learning Systems

#### Education

# **University of Glasgow**

2019 - 2023

Awarded an upper second, 2:1, BSc in computing science

#### Top module grades:

Database Systems – B3 Professional Software Development – A5 Text as Data – A4 Cyber Security Fundamentals – A5 Recommender Systems – A5 Level 4 individual project/dissertation – A4
Forensics (Masters level) – B2
Robotics Foundations – B1
Systems Programming – A4
Secured Software Engineering (Masters level) – A

# **North Berwick High School**

2013 - 2019

Achieved 4 highers with an additional 2 advanced highers in Computing Science and Graphic Communications

# Work Experience

## Barista/ Kitchen assistant, Cake Cafe

07/2023 - Present

Working within a cafe as a barista/ kitchen assistant with a small team. Attending to customers' needs and efficiently resolving any issues that occur.

- Achieved a pass in a food and service safety check by maintaining a clean and safe environment for customers and staff
- Saved major losses by quickly adapting to a new role in the kitchen due to staff issues.
- Lowered business costs and increased income by identifying wasteful stock and non-logical pricing on cafe items.
- Increased customer satisfaction and comfort by renovating the cafe

# **Bartender/ Waiter, Gullane Golf Club**

05/2021 - 08/2022

Worked as a bartender/ waiter in my local golf club. Providing excellent customer service within a fast-paced environment.

- Successfully launched a new clubhouse that quickly became the new favourite of the members
- Increased efficiency and safety by identifying key issues in the work system when first opening the clubhouse.
- Improved customer satisfaction by training new staff members in faster and safer ways to handle food and drinks, maintaining the level of standards expected by members.

## **Projects**

#### **Year 3 Group Project**

As part of my 3rd-year studies I participated in a group project which consisted of fully developing a software system with a designated customer. This was my first large group project and I gained new skills including, working effectively with a new team of people, organizing and carrying out meetings with a real-world customer, managing and delivering on deadlines and problem solving issues. We designed and produced a fully working learning web app which teaches children how to count and group by numbers.

https://rwg1234.github.io/sticks/www/

#### Year 4 Individual Project

As part of my 4<sup>th</sup> year studies, the majority of credits were for an individual project where we had the opportunity to work with a lecturer to build a system based on a topic they selected. My project was a website hosting an email sensitivity classifier, this website would take in a collection of emails and using a machine learning algorithm, would find any sensitive data that may be within each email. This was my first large scale individual project and it taught me many new skills, including individual time management, coordinating with subject matter experts, taking on board new suggestions and implementing them efficiently and safely. This project also included a dissertation based on the development process throughout the year. This was the first professional paper I had ever written and provided me the chance to take all the research, planning and reflections from development and convey it to others in a structured and readable manner. https://github.com/Lewis891/identifying-and-protecting-personal-information-in-email-search

### **Hobbies and Interests**

#### Golf

I enjoy playing golf with my family and friends as I have grown up around the sport and it allows me to keep fit, socialize and meet new people

#### **Coding events**

Whenever the opportunity arises my friends and I love to take part in hackathons and coding challenges. It is a fun way to socialize, and it allows us to build on skills developed throughout our degrees.

During my final year we participated in the 2023 Code Olympics. Sponsors including JP Morgan, Morgan Stanley, SAS, and the School of Computing Science, provided challenges for teams to tackle over the course of 24 hours. Whilst it was expected for teams to spend the time focusing on one set of challenges, we decided to give them all a go. In doing so, we won 3 out of the 4 sponsor challenges and the overall trophy that year.